VINCENT R. SÁNCHEZ

Javascript Engineer

Summary

I am a web developer with a love for building web apps and a passion for using Javascript and cutting-edge front- and back-end technology to deliver awesome user experiences. Over the course of three years, my drive to bring ideas to life has transformed me from a casual hobbyist to a seasoned professional looking to collaborate with others on creating the next big thing. I am particularly fond of React.js with its emphasis on unidirectional data flow and functional programming concepts, as I believe these are powerful tenets for enforcing sane state management within complex applications.

Experience

Spotible, Product Development Engineer, New York, NY September 2015 – Present

Built, tested and maintained production code serving dozens of the biggest industry name brands and companies (Hearst, ABC, Rolling Stone, Jaguar, Hillary Clinton PAC, Newsweek, Tribune, Reebok).

Wrote and maintained a VAST / VPAID video player serving as the cornerstone of the company's programmatic ad services, generating millions of video impressions across the globe.

Teamed with iOS / Android developers to spearhead the business's emerging native app experiences.

Implemented Node.js / Bash scripts for testing network requests and RESTful API debugging.

National Necrotizing Fasciitis Foundation, Web Developer, *Remote*May 2013 – September 2015

Implemented top to bottom overhaul of non-profit organization's website.

Upgraded look and feel of webpage, incorporating responsive design principles, and greatly enhancing the user experience for the company's mobile audience.

U.S. Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, Intern, New York, NY January – April 2012

Maintained FOIA IMS database using CRUD functionality to handle data entries on pending charges.

Various Non-technical roles, New York, NY

2006 - 2014

Restaurant industry, volunteer work and internships. Accepted to UC Berkeley School of Law (declined offer to pursue career writing code).

Education

John Jay College of Criminal Justice New York, NY 2005, 2009-2013

BA, Political Science, magna cum laude

GPA: 3.79, GPA in Major: 3.88

Senior Thesis: Twitter Interaction Among Members of the 113th Congress

Used R programming language for statistical analysis

Key Skills

KNOWLEDGE OF

Node.js
React.js
Redux
Webpack
Bootstrap
jQuery

Bash Terminal • AJAX

Git • HTML5 / CSS3

KEY COMPENTENCIES

- Comprehensive experience coding client- and server-side Javascript.
- The boundless curiosity needed to keep up with the break-neck rate of change in the tools and techniques of modern web development.
- Appreciation for unit tests, and the role they play for developing clean, modular code.
- The capacity to thrive both independently and as part of a collaborative team effort.

RECENT PROJECTS / OPEN SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS

TwoBlocks

Game built using Google Maps API in conjunction with React. Players are shown random panoramas from NYC and must guess where the Street View came from.

Tweet Cloud

Web app that uses Twitter API to search tweets, and arranges them into an interactive three-dimensional sphere. Used Bootstrap, AJAX, jQuery, PHP.

ShopScraper

Single-page web application using Node.js to scrape product data from local grocery stores for increased personal shopping savings. UI built with React.

JsTagSphere

Identified source of bug that prevented proper rendering of content when doctype declared, making cool software impractical for use in HTML5. Fix allowed me to incorporate the code into the Tweet Cloud.

HOBBIES AND INTERESTS

Before code, there was music. I have played guitar for 16 years and I love discovering new music, especially hip hop, punk and indie rock. In my free time I enjoy cooking or traveling around the city to try new food.

COMMUNITY PRESENCE

GitHub (tdbts)
Stack Overflow (tdbts)
Twitter (VRSanchez8717)

CONTACT DETAILS

Vincent R. Sánchez 1326 65th Street Brooklyn, NY 11219

T: 347-255-3115 E: VinnySanchez87@gmail.com

